<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>R on Peter Finnerty</title>
    <link>/tags/r/</link>
    <description>Recent content in R on Peter Finnerty</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/r/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictive Models: Seattle Home Prices</title>
      <link>/post/predictive-models-seattle-home-prices/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/predictive-models-seattle-home-prices/</guid>
      <description>This is my final presentation for Analytics and Business Intelligence, a course I completed during my senior year at BC.
  In this project, I used linear regressions to explain what casues home prices and predictive models (Logistic, Naive Bayes, and Decision Tree) to identify highly priced homes. Here is the dataset used for this project, which is from Kaggle and focues on King County, Washington.
In the coming days, I’ll post a markdown file with much of the code used to produce this presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Oxford MPI Data</title>
      <link>/post/oxford-mpi-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/oxford-mpi-data/</guid>
      <description>MPI Background MPI scores represent the best operationalized non-income based approach to measuring poverty. It measures acute poverty, including those who are poor due to absolute deprivation in one necessity and those who experience multiple forms of deprivation that result in poverty. This approach captures the spirit of Amartya Sen’s idea of shifting from income-based poverty metrics to a capabilities understanding of poverty and deprivation. For an overview of the issues with income-based poverty metrics and the importance of other measures, see Laderchi, Saith, and Stewart (2003).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>